<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- SPDX-FileCopyrightText: (C) 2012 - 2026 Synergy App Ltd -->
<!-- SPDX-License-Identifier: CC0-1.0 -->
<component type="desktop-application">
	<id>com.symless.synergy</id>
	<metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
	<project_license>GPL-2.0-only</project_license>
	<name>Synergy</name>
	<developer id="com.symless">
		<name>Synergy App Ltd</name>
	</developer>
	<summary>Share one keyboard and mouse between computers</summary>
	<description>
		<p>
			Use the keyboard, mouse, or trackpad of one computer to control nearby computers, and work
			seamlessly between them.
		</p>
	</description>
	<launchable type="desktop-id">com.symless.synergy.desktop</launchable>
	<url type="homepage">https://symless.com/synergy</url>
	<provides>
		<id>com.symless.synergy.desktop</id>
	</provides>
	<categories>
		<category>Utility</category>
	</categories>
	<keywords>
		<keyword>Input</keyword>
		<keyword>Sharing</keyword>
		<keyword translate="no">KVM</keyword>
	</keywords>
	<branding>
		<color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#dddddd</color>
		<color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#555555</color>
	</branding>
	<content_rating type="oars-1.0" />
	<releases>
		<release version="1.21.0" date="2026-06-02" urgency="medium">
			<description>
				<p>
					This release folds a large number of upstream improvements into Synergy from Deskflow,
					much of it built by the Synergy team and contributed upstream.
					Highlights since the previous release:
				</p>
				<p>Stronger security</p>
				<ul>
					<li>TLS fingerprints are now kept in a fingerprint database, with a clearer comparison
						dialog that shows both the local and remote prints side by side.</li>
					<li>A new option for servers to require a client certificate before accepting a
						connection.</li>
				</ul>
				<p>Reliability</p>
				<ul>
					<li>The app now connects to the running core process over a dedicated IPC channel and
						receives status updates directly, instead of inferring the connection state by parsing
						log output.</li>
					<li>Only one copy of the core runs at a time, so duplicate instances no longer fight over
						the connection.</li>
					<li>On Windows, clipboard changes are tracked with a modern format-listener API for more
						reliable clipboard sharing.</li>
				</ul>
				<p>Features and interface</p>
				<ul>
					<li>A single combined core binary replaces the separate client and server processes.</li>
					<li>A hotkey to cycle through computers, and an option to start with the cursor locked
						to the current computer.</li>
					<li>An option to show the version in the window title.</li>
					<li>The server address can be a list of host names or IP addresses, with a more accurate
						suggested address that updates as the network changes.</li>
					<li>A new client configuration dialog, a searchable log you can dock and hide, millisecond
						timestamps, and a refreshed about dialog and status area.</li>
					<li>A setting to choose the network protocol (Synergy or Barrier) for compatibility with
						different clients.</li>
					<li>Live interface translation without restarting, with Spanish, Italian, Japanese,
						Chinese (simplified), Korean, and Russian added.</li>
					<li>Mono or colorful tray icons with matching light and dark icon themes.</li>
					<li>A new scroll scaling option replaces the old scroll-speed setting.</li>
					<li>On Linux, server and client configuration honors XDG_CONFIG_HOME.</li>
				</ul>
				<p>See the release notes for the full changelog.</p>
			</description>
			<url>https://symless.com/synergy/download</url>
		</release>
	</releases>
</component>
